# **Akash Giri**

Phone number: (+1) 4374601743 (Mobile) | Email address: akashgiri2055@gmail.com | Website:

akash1998.vercel.app/ | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/akash-giri-449597184/ | Github: github.com/akashgiri1998 |

Address: Flora Dr, 192, M1P 1A9, Scarborough, Canada (Work)

# ABOUT ME

Software developer with a 3 years of professional experience as a Mobile Application Developer. My expertise extends to crafting elegant and responsive UIs, implementing complex functionalities, and optimizing performance to meet and exceed client expectations. Moreover, successfully built mobile apps from the scratch and ensuring their performance with the successful deployment on the Play Store. My expertise extends to crafting elegant and responsive UIs, implementing complex functionalities, and optimizing performance to meet and exceed client expectations.

# WORK EXPERIENCE

06/2022 - 12/2022 Kathmandu, Nepal

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER TOUCHWARE I.T. NEPAL PVT. LTD. (KOTUKO, ITALY)

- Led the development of Vinhood, a wine recommendation platform, achieving a 20% increase in user engagement within the first three months of launch.
- Translated wireframes into a seamless user experience, resulting in a 25% reduction in bounce rates and a 30% increase in user satisfaction based on post-launch surveys.
- Diagnosed and resolved bugs and performance issues, leading to a 20% improvement in application responsiveness and a 15% decrease in crash rates, enhancing overall user experience.
- Implemented Storybook to streamline the development and testing of UI components, reducing development time by 25% as measured by code review feedback and post-release bug reports.

11/2020 - 05/2022 Bhaktapur, Nepal

# MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER(FREELANCING) DIGISPIRED TECHNOLOGIES PVT. LTD.

- Facilitated clear and concise communication with clients, ensuring seamless integration of features in outsourcing projects. Achieved a 15% improvement in client satisfaction scores based on post-delivery feedback.
- Delivered efficient mobile app features to meet client requirements, resulting in a 20% reduction in post-launch bug reports and a 25% increase in user adoption rates within the first month.
- Integrated APIs for robust server connectivity, enhancing overall application performance and achieving a 30% reduction in data loading times.
- Implemented GraphQL in accordance with project requirements, leading to a 25% enhancement in data querying and manipulation capabilities.

11/2020 - 12/2021 United States

# JUNIOR MOBILE APPLICATION DEVELOPER SOFTHOVER

- Created a ReactJS-based admin interface for the website, meeting project requirements and enhancing the platform's administrative capabilities.
- Successfully transitioned an existing React web app of TripLocator to React Native, achieving a unified codebase and streamlining the development process.
- Employed Redux for robust state management in both the React Native mobile app and ReactJS web app, ensuring efficient data flow and optimal app performance. This implementation resulted in a 15% decrease in app crashes and improved overall user experience.
- Published the TripLocator mobile app on the PlayStore, achieving a milestone in project completion. The app garnered positive reviews, with a 4.5-star rating, and attracted a 20% increase in downloads within the first month

#### EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/2023 - CURRENT Canada

# ONTARIO COLLEGE GRADUATE CERTIFICATE ON COMPUTER SOFTWARE AND DATABASE DEVELOPMENT Loyalist College

Address Victoria Park Avenue, Toronto, Canada

08/2016 - 10/2020 Nepal

**BACHELOR IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING** Kathmandu University

Address Dhulikhel, Kavre, Nepal | Final grade Score: 3.31 out of 4

# LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **NEPALI** 

Other language(s): ENGLISH, HINDI

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

# **SKILLS**

# **Technical Skills**

#### **Front-End Development:**

- HTML, CSS, React.js, React Native CLI, Expo, Redux, Bootstrap, AntDesign, JavaScript, TypeScript
- REST APIs (consumed and integrated within the front-end), Storybook (UI component development and testing)

#### **Back-End Development:**

Node.js, Express.js, SQL (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), GraphQL, Python, Java, PHP etc.

# DevOps & Tools:

• Docker, GitHub, Babel, Jira (Project Management and Issue Tracking), AWS (Amazon Web Services)

# **Professional Skills**

• Communication, Leadership, Collaboration, Problem Solving, Adaptability, Time Management, Critical Thinking and Continuous Learning

#### PARTICIPATIONS/CERTIFICATIONS

10/12/2019 - 20/12/2019

Second Nepal Winter School in Artificial Intelligence(AI)

15/12/2018 - 17/12/2018

Startup Workshop, KU Innovation and Entrepreneurship Community

28/12/2018 - 29/12/2018

Startup Competition, IT MEET by KUCC

05/2019

**Designer of IT Express, KUCC** 

22/12/2018

Volunteer of Warm Clothes Collection, KU Youth Red Cross Circle(KUYRCC)

# **REFERENCES**

# Basanta Raj Pudasaini

Director of Operations and Business Development | Takeo | New York, United States | basanta@takeo.ai | <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/basantapudasaini/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/basantapudasaini/</a> | +1-437-499-8272